Once we have implemented our tracking algorithm,
追跡アルゴリズムを実装したら そのパフォーマンスをチェックして
we might want to check its performance
推定結果と
in terms of how far the estimated result is from the true result.
実際の結果の差を確認することを お勧めします
There are many evaluation metrics, but
評価メトリックはたくさんありますが
perhaps the most common one is the so-called root mean squared error.
おそらく最も一般的なものは 平均二乗平方根誤差です
In the context of tracking, it's an accuracy metric used to
トラッキングののコンテキストでは これは推定状態と
measure the deviation of the estimated state from the true state.
実際の状態の偏差を測定するために使用される 精度測定基準です
So let's see how it's computed.
それでは計算方法を見てみましょう
At the given processing step, I basically need two values,
所定の処理ステップでは 基本的に推定状態と実際の値の2つの値が必要です
the estimated state which is a vector with a position and velocity components,
推定状態は位置と速度のコンポーネントを含むベクターであり 実際の値は一般的に
and the real values that are usually known as ground truth values.
地上検証データ値として 知られています
The difference between the estimated state and
推定状態と 地上検証データとの差は
the ground truth state gives me a so called, residual.
残差と 呼ばれます
These residuals are squared and averaged and
これらの残差を二乗し 平均化し
finally the square root gives me the error metric.
最後に平方根を計算して 誤差測定基準を求めることができます
The lower is the error, the higher is our estimation accuracy.
誤差が小さいほど 推定精度は高くなります
Let's see how it works in C++.
C++ではどうなるでしょうか
So, I'm giving you a starting code.
スターティングコードを用意しておきました
I want you to complete CalculateRMSE function, which takes a list
推定状態のリストに対応する 地上検証データのリストを取得する
of estimated states, and another list of corresponding ground truth states.
CalculateRMSE関数を 完成させましょう
It returns a vector with a root mean square error of the position and
この関数は 位置と速度の平均二乗平方根誤差を持つ
velocity.
ベクターを返します
Also consider that you have to check for
2つのベクター 推定値と地上検証データの場合は
invalid inputs in the case of the two vectors, estimations and ground truths.
無効な入力をチェックする必要があることも 考慮してください
The estimation vector should be non-empty and
推定ベクターは 空であってはならず
it has to be the same size as the ground truth vector.
地上検証データベクターと 同じサイズでなければなりません
So you will have to use the Eigen functions to perform
そのため 固有関数を使って 必要な演算を
all the necessary operations.
すべて行う必要があります
You might want to subtract the vector from another vector as in this example.
この例のように ベクターをもう1つのベクターから 減算することをお勧めします
You also can do the coefficient-wise multiplications as here, or
このように係数ごとの乗算を実行することも あるいはこのように
you can compute the vector element square root as here.
ベクター要素の平方根を 計算することもできます